<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ROOT><record id="00025576" dt="2016-06-03"><version>4</version><date format="yyyy-mm-dd">2013-05-29</date><date_nonpreferred_format></date_nonpreferred_format><cms_record_id></cms_record_id><title>SAMPLE: Interview with Steve  Zahn, May 29, 2013</title><accession>2013OH132 WW 401</accession><duration>1:17:0</duration><collection_id>OHWW</collection_id><collection_name>Colonel Arthur L. Kelly American Veterans Oral History Collection</collection_name><series_id>WW010</series_id><series_name>From Combat to Kentucky: Student Veteran Oral History Project </series_name><repository>Louie B. Nunn Center for Oral History, University of Kentucky Libraries</repository><funding></funding><repository_url /><subject>Iraq War, 2003-2011.</subject><interviewee>Steve Zahn</interviewee><interviewer>Doug Boyd</interviewer><file_name></file_name><sync></sync><sync_alt></sync_alt><transcript_alt_lang></transcript_alt_lang><translate>0</translate><media_id></media_id><media_url>http://youtu.be/gyJk1UfWrRs</media_url><mediafile><host>Kaltura</host><host_account_id></host_account_id><host_player_id></host_player_id><host_clip_id></host_clip_id><clip_format>video</clip_format></mediafile><kembed>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/2106141/sp/210614100/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/34339901/partner_id/2106141?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player_1462211853&amp;entry_id=1_ai13y70d&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozAllowFullScreen frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</kembed><language></language><index><point><time>0</time><title>Interview Introduction</title><partial_transcript>Ok,well,  we're here with Steve Zahn, this is Doug Boyd. We are going to do an oral history interview for the Louie B. Nunn Center for Oral History at the University of Kentucky Libraries</partial_transcript><synopsis>An introduction to the interview with Steve Zahn.</synopsis><keywords>

</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>43</time><title>Brief biography</title><partial_transcript>If you would, begin by telling us a little bit about yourself</partial_transcript><synopsis>Discusses childhood in Minnesota, his fascination with the military and his training as an actor at Harvard University and his transition into professional acting.  Mentions the film &quot;Reality Bites,&quot; his first film in 1993.</synopsis><keywords>Broadway;Gustavus Adolphus College;Institute for Advanced Theater Training at American Repertory Theater at Harvard University;Minnesota;New York City</keywords><subjects>Actors--United States</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>122</time><title>Moving to Kentucky</title><partial_transcript>You are also here in Kentucky, talk about that transition.</partial_transcript><synopsis>Talks about meeting his wife Robyn Peterman and moving their family to Kentucky and his interest in Kentucky history.</synopsis><keywords>Historical markers;Kentucky history</keywords><subjects>Kentucky</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>282</time><title>Lifelong interest in the military</title><partial_transcript>Let's talk about Minnesota, a bit.  </partial_transcript><synopsis>Talks about developing a childhood interest in the military, a family trip to Gettysburg and his love for military movies.  Remembers how he often pretended to be a soldier as a child.  Specifically talks about the influence of a book about the Vietnam War that was so powerful that he made copies of the pages of the book and handed them out to people on the street. The importance of supporting veterans.</synopsis><keywords>Marines;Minnesota</keywords><subjects>Childhood and youth;Gettysburg National Military Park (Pa.)</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>620</time><title>Becoming a professional actor</title><partial_transcript>You actually made the call to go into acting as opposed to going into the military</partial_transcript><synopsis>Talks about dropping out of school to pursue acting and how this came as no surprise to his parents.  Discusses the influence of High School teachers and his experiences at the American Repertory Theatre at Harvard University.  Discusses the transition from acting on stage to acting in movies.  </synopsis><keywords>American Repertory Theatre, Harvard University;Ben Stiller;Encouragement from Parents;Ethan Hawke;Parents;Reality Bites (Film)</keywords><subjects>Acting;Acting--Study and teaching;Harvard University;High school teachers</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>1008</time><title>Working in films</title><partial_transcript>So you've done a couple films, what was the first &quot;War&quot; film</partial_transcript><synopsis>Talks about specific roles, including roles he did not get; and being typecasted into comedic  roles.  Specifically discusses the films &quot;That Thing You Do&quot; and &quot;Rescue Dawn.&quot;  Reflects on the advantages of being &quot;typecasted.&quot;  Talks about the research process for &quot;Rescue Dawn,&quot; the decision to not do &quot;Band of Brothers,&quot; and his hope for a role in &quot;Saving Private Ryan.&quot;  Discusses Werner Herzog's approach to filming &quot;Rescue Dawn.&quot; </synopsis><keywords>Band of Brothers (Film);Comedy;Courage Under Fire (Film);Crimson Tide (Film);Dale Dye;Deiter Dangler;Duane W. Martin;Joyride (Film);Rescue Dawn (Film);That Thing You Do (Film);Tom Hanks;Werner Herzog</keywords><subjects>Acting;Comedy</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>1490</time><title>LIfelong Interest in the military and acting</title><partial_transcript>You have this amazing story about...I like the idea of connecting it to playing &quot;pretend&quot; as a child, the story of the letter.</partial_transcript><synopsis>Returns to the topic of early influences on his fascination with the military, watching &quot;the World at War,&quot; and how as a child he loved to check out books about the military.  Connects his early interest in military to his professional career as an actor.</synopsis><keywords>Lawrence Olivier;the National World War II Museum;The World at War (Documentary);Vietnam War;World War II</keywords><subjects>Vietnam War;World War, 1939-1945</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>1690</time><title>Visiting the Troops in Iraq</title><partial_transcript>At some point, you've reached a level of fame</partial_transcript><synopsis>Reflects on his role as a celebrity and his passion for serving and advocating for veterans.  Discusses being invited by Pro Sports MVP for the &quot;Ambassadors of Hollywood Tour&quot;  to Iraq to visit the troops.  Talks about preparations for his visit; the journey to Iraq, flying in Blackhawk Helicopters.  </synopsis><keywords>Blackhawk Helicopters;Camp Bucca;Iraq;Kuwait;Veterans</keywords><subjects>Iraq War;Veterans--Services for--United States</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>2313</time><title>Into the Combat Zone</title><partial_transcript>Did you have a moment on that flight, thinking back on that again, that you realized that this wasn't pretend?</partial_transcript><synopsis>Discusses details about his experience in Iraq, impressions of the cafeteria; his general excitement, and his interaction with the troops.  </synopsis><keywords>Camp Bucca;Camp Ramadi;Iraq</keywords><subjects>Iraq War</subjects><gps>30.034167, 47.929444</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>Umm Qasr, Iraq</gps_text><hyperlink>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5_x0XuA3hjk</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>Video footage of the &quot;Ambassadors of Hollywood&quot; trip to Iraq.  </hyperlink_text></point><point><time>2558</time><title>Interacting with the troops in Iraq: Part I</title><partial_transcript>I know you probably don't Google yourself, but those photos are online</partial_transcript><synopsis>Describes personal interactions with the troops.  Recalls shooting a .50 caliber gun; running in a July 4th race;  Using humor to help boost moral.  Tells a specific story about participating in a boxing match with a female officer.</synopsis><keywords>Iraq</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>http://imgur.com/gallery/NMnJh</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>Images of Steve Zahn interacting with the troops in Iraq.</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>2907</time><title>Interacting with the troops in Iraq Part II</title><partial_transcript>Camp Bucca was cool.  And then just talking with these guys</partial_transcript><synopsis>Reflects on the personal stories told and the friendships made during his visit.  Talks about visiting &quot;FOBs&quot; (Forward Operating Bases).  </synopsis><keywords>Al Asad Airbase;Camp Bucca;Forward Operating Base (FOB);Iraq;Korean Village;Veterans</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>3212</time><title>Interacting with the troops in Iraq: Part III</title><partial_transcript>Did you ever have a moment when you were, kind of afraid?</partial_transcript><synopsis>Recalls moments during his visit in Iraq, including a night interacting with British SAS troops.  Describes visiting Sadaam Hussein's palace.  </synopsis><keywords>Blackhawk Helicopter;Sadaam Hussein;the Green Zone</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>3481</time><title>Boosting morale: An unforgettable trip</title><partial_transcript>Boyd: We had an interview come in, we did an interview with a gentleman,  for this project, who was in a combat support role. </partial_transcript><synopsis>Boyd and Zahn discuss the role of morale in the lives of the troops.  Zahn describes his &quot;mission,&quot; wanting to make people laugh.  Tells a story about having dinner with a group of soldiers who had just returned from a mission where they lost troops and his efforts to engage them and boost their morale.   Tells a powerful story about flying out of Iraq seated next to a woman who wept as the plane took off.</synopsis><keywords>Humor;Morale</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>3860</time><title>Connecting with veterans back home</title><partial_transcript>Yeah, and just having... Now, the beauty of that trip...now when I run into a vet, I have a doorway.  </partial_transcript><synopsis>Reflects on how his trip to Iraq has improved his ability to connect to veterans.  Tells a story about interacting with veterans while working on the TV series Treme in New Orleans.  Discusses activism and the importance of supporting the troops when they are both &quot;clean&quot; and when they are &quot;dirty and broken.&quot;  </synopsis><keywords>Morale;Transition;Veterans</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point><point><time>4188</time><title>Honoring Veterans: The Importance of Oral History</title><partial_transcript>I am definitely going to go on more trips</partial_transcript><synopsis>Talks about how he wants to continue to serve the troops.  Discusses the importance of doing projects like the Nunn Center's &quot;From Combat to Kentucky Oral History Project.&quot;  Zahn and Boyd discuss the importance of recording oral history. </synopsis><keywords>Oral history;student veterans;Veterans</keywords><subjects>

</subjects><gps>

</gps><gps_zoom></gps_zoom><gps_text>

</gps_text><hyperlink>

</hyperlink><hyperlink_text>

</hyperlink_text></point></index><index_alt></index_alt><type>Oral History</type><description>[Sample] Actor Steve Zahn discusses his childhood in Minnesota,  his transition into professional acting and a lifelong fascination with the military.  Reflects on his interest for serving and advocating for veterans. Discusses being invited by Pro Sports MVP for the &quot;Ambassadors of Hollywood Tour&quot; to Iraq to visit the troops. Talks about preparations for his visit, the journey to Iraq,  the day to day interactions with the troops and the overall impact of the trip on his life.</description><rel /><transcript>No transcript.</transcript><transcript_alt></transcript_alt><rights>All rights to the interviews, including but not restricted to legal title, copyrights and literary property rights, have been transferred to the University of Kentucky Libraries. This interview record been provided as a sample and cannot be reproduced or distributed outside of your OHMS setup without permission.  </rights><fmt>video</fmt><usage>Interviews may only be reproduced with permission from Louie B. Nunn Center for Oral History, Special Collections and Digital Programs, University of Kentucky Libraries. This interview record been provided as a sample and cannot be reproduced or distributed outside of your OHMS setup without permission.  </usage><userestrict>0</userestrict><xmllocation>https://oralhistory.uky.edu/oh/render.php?cachefile=OHMS-Sample-002.xml</xmllocation><xmlfilename>OHMS-Sample-002.xml</xmlfilename><collection_link></collection_link><series_link>https://www.kentuckyoralhistory.org/catalog/xt734t6f4g1b</series_link><translate>0</translate></record></ROOT>